Eugenics Record Office Records 1670-1964 Mss.Ms.Coll.77
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Trait Files, 1670-1964 (Box Series I: 1-65)
  - A:81022 - A:884 #3 (Box Series I-59)
    - Blood Pressure, 1924-1927; A:8341 #1 (Box Series I-59)
    - High Blood Pressure, 1923-1934; A:8341 #2 (Box Series I-59)
    - Low Blood Pressure, 1927, 1933; A:8342 (Box Series I-59)
    - Aorta, 1934; A:8352 (Box Series I-59)
    - Embolism; Thrombosis, 1923-1932; A:836 (Box Series I-59)
    - Varicose Veins, 1927, 1930; A:837 (Box Series I-59)
    - Other Diseases and Defects, 1926-1934; A:839 (Box Series I-59)
    - Lymphatic System, 1928; A:85 (Box Series I-59)
    - General, 1926, 1928; A:850 (Box Series I-59)
    - Lymphatic Stasis, 1923-1924; A:8503 (Box Series I-59)
    - Spleen, 1923-1924; A:86 (Box Series I-59)
    - Splenic Anemia, 1904, 1920; A:863 (Box Series I-59)
    - Spleen, Hereditary Enlargement of, 1823-1925; A:864 (Box Series I-59)
    - Haemolitic Icterus, 1925, 1933; A:8691 #1 (Box Series I-59)
    - Hemolytic Jaundice, 1922-1935; A:8691 #2 (Box Series I-59)
    - Thymus Gland, 1905-1906, 1931; A:87 (Box Series I-59)
    - Hypertrophy of Thymus, 1901; A:871 (Box Series I-59)
    - Thyroid Gland, 1908-1934; A:88 (Box Series I-59)
    - Thyroiditis, 1917, 1922; A:8801 (Box Series I-59)
    - Hypothyroidism, 1919-1934; A:8802 (Box Series I-59)
    - Hyperthyroidism, 1926, 1934; A:8803 (Box Series I-59)
    - Cretinism, 1915-1934; A:882 (Box Series I-59)
    - Goitre, 1908-1932; A:884 #1 (Box Series I-59)
    - Goiter Studies, 1932; A:884 #2 (Box Series I-59)
    - Goiter Studies, 1932; A:884 #3 (Box Series I-59)
  - A:884 #4 - A:94348 (Box Series I-60)
    - Goiter Studies, 1932; A:884 #4 (Box Series I-60)
    - Goiter Studies, 1932; A:884 #5 (Box Series I-60)
    - Goiter Studies, 1932; A:884 #6 (Box Series I-60)
    - Myxedema, 1923, 1927; A:888 (Box Series I-60)
    - Endocrine Glands, 1915-1929; A:89 (Box Series I-60)
    - Internal Secretions, 1913-1925; A:890 (Box Series I-60)
    - Pineal Gland, 1914; A:891 (Box Series I-60)
    - Pituitary Gland, 1909-1915; A:892 (Box Series I-60)
    - Suprarenal Gland, 1920, 1928; A:8991 (Box Series I-60)
    - Excretions, 1926; A:901 (Box Series I-60)
    - Uraemia, 1890; A:9011 (Box Series I-60)
    - Steatorrhea, 1913; A:9013 (Box Series I-60)
    - Alkaptonuria, 1901-1923; A:902 (Box Series I-60)
    - Chyluria, 1918; A:903 (Box Series I-60)
    - Cystinuria, 1902-1929; A:904 (Box Series I-60)
    - Hematuria, 1902-1923; A:906 (Box Series I-60)
    - Hemoglobinuria, 1932; A:907 (Box Series I-60)
    - Albuminuria, 1877-1923; A:908 (Box Series I-60)
    - Kidney, n.d.; A:91 (Box Series I-60)
    - Kidney--Cystic, 1902, 1925; A:910 (Box Series I-60)
    - Nephritis--Chronic, 1924, 1927; A:912 (Box Series I-60)
    - Nephritis, 1893-1924; A:913 (Box Series I-60)
    - Bright's Disease, 1881-1919; A:914 (Box Series I-60)
    - Other Diseases of the Kidney, 1925-1934; A:918 (Box Series I-60)
    - Bladder, n.d.; A:92 (Box Series I-60)
    - Bladder--Calculus, 1884; A:922 (Box Series I-60)
    - Other Defects, 1922; A:929 (Box Series I-60)
    - Urethra--Congenital Malformation, 1933; A:9342 (Box Series I-60)
    - Hypospadias, 1884, 1889; A:9347 (Box Series I-60)
    - Genito-Urinary Organs, 1929; A:9394 (Box Series I-60)
    - Reproductive System, 1920; A:94 (Box Series I-60)
    - Sterility, 1904-1917; A:9412 (Box Series I-60)
    - Amenorrhea, 1911, 1920; A:9414 (Box Series I-60)
    - Dysmenorrhea, 1905, 1910; A:9415 (Box Series I-60)
    - Menopause, 1919; A:9417 (Box Series I-60)
    - Precocity, 1920, 1923; A:9418 (Box Series I-60)
    - Female Precocity, 1903; A:94182 (Box Series I-60)
    - Sterilization, 1912-1934; A:942 (Box Series I-60)
    - Ovary, 1911; A:9434 (Box Series I-60)
    - Physiology of, 1911, 1926; A:943401 (Box Series I-60)
    - Menstruation, 1910; A:943402 (Box Series I-60)
    - Corpus Luteum of, 1917; A:943406 (Box Series I-60)
    - Regeneration of Female Organs, 1890-1906; A:94343 (Box Series I-60)
    - Cysts and Tumors of Ovary, 1905-1932; A:94346 (Box Series I-60)
    - Ovariotomy Sterilization, 1873-1925; A:94348 (Box Series I-60)
  - A:9436 - A:974 x 6 #4 (Box Series I-61)
    - Uterus, 1861; A:9436 (Box Series I-61)
    - Congenital Malformation, 1914-1923; A:94362 (Box Series I-61)
    - Male Sex Organs, 1911; A:945 (Box Series I-61)
    - Eunuchoidism, 1909-1924; A:94512 (Box Series I-61)
    - Varicocoele, 1930; A:94513 (Box Series I-61)
    - Hermaphroditism, 1884-1931; A:94515 (Box Series I-61)
    - Testis, 1921; A:9452 (Box Series I-61)
    - Testis, Atrophy of, 1902; A:94523 (Box Series I-61)
    - Cryptotorchism, 1903-1929; A:94526 (Box Series I-61)
    - Vasectomy, 1911-1912; A:94529 (Box Series I-61)
    - Prostate Gland, 1923, 1926; A:9453 (Box Series I-61)
    - Phimosis, n.d.; A:94541 (Box Series I-61)
    - Other Deformities of Male Sex Organs, 1917, 1919; A:9459 (Box Series I-61)
    - Puerperal State, 1922; A:96 (Box Series I-61)
    - Accidents of Pregnancy, 1917-1918; A:962 (Box Series I-61)
    - Abortion, 1913-1932; A:9621 (Box Series I-61)
    - Miscarriage, 1913-1915; A:9622 (Box Series I-61)
    - Ectopic Gestation, 1927; A:9624 (Box Series I-61)
    - Tubal Pregnancy, 1918; A:9626 (Box Series I-61)
    - Premature (Living) Birth, n.d.; A:96261 (Box Series I-61)
    - Premature Birth, 1928; A:96261 (Box Series I-61)
    - Monstrosities, 1921; A:9627 (Box Series I-61)
    - Convulsions, n.d.; A:9628 (Box Series I-61)
    - Puerperal Hemorrhage, 1929; A:963 (Box Series I-61)
    - Caesarian Section, n.d.; A:9641 (Box Series I-61)
    - Immigration, 1670-1929; A:97 #1 (Box Series I-61)
    - Race, 1910-1932; A:97 #2 (Box Series I-61)
    - Race x Hair, 1906; A:97 x 14 (Box Series I-61)
    - Race x Head, 1923; A:97 x 22 (Box Series I-61)
    - Epilepsy--Race Incidence, 1865-1922; A:97 x 314 (Box Series I-61)
    - Race Crossing in Ukraine, 1931; A:97 x 97477 (Box Series I-61)
    - Race Crossing--North Africa, 1929; A:97 x 9761 (Box Series I-61)
    - Caucasian Mountain Whites, 1927; A:974 (Box Series I-61)
    - Race x Mental Traits (Europe), 1921; A:974 x 4 (Box Series I-61)
    - Caucasian x Mongolian, 1909-1921; A:974 x 5 (Box Series I-61)
    - Caucasian x Negro, 1891-1927; A:974 x 6 #1 (Box Series I-61)
      - "How to Keep Well: Results of Mixing the Races", 1927; A:974 x 6-15 (Box Series I-61)
      - "Interesting Researches by the Carnegie Institution Disprove the Popular Notion that a 'Pass-for-White' Person Married to a Pure White May Have a Negro Child", A:974 x 6-17 (Box Series I-61)
    - Caucasian x Negro--McDonough Family, n.d.; A:974 x 6 #2 (Box Series I-61)
    - Caucasian x Negro--Jamaica Negro Males, 1928; A:974 x 6 #3 (Box Series I-61)
    - Caucasian x Negro--Jamaica Negro Females, 1928; A:974 x 6 #4 (Box Series I-61)
  - A:974 x 6 #5 - A:974 x 6 x 7 #2 (Box Series I-62)
    - Caucasian x Negro--Jamaica Mulatto Males, 1928; A:974 x 6 #5 (Box Series I-62)
    - Caucasian x Negro--Jamaica Mulatto Males, 1928; A:974 x 6 #6 (Box Series I-62)
    - Caucasian x Negro--Jamaica Mulatto Females, 1928; A:974 x 6 #7 (Box Series I-62)
    - Caucasian x Negro--Jamaica Mulatto Females, 1928; A:974 x 6 #8 (Box Series I-62)
    - Caucasian x Negro--Jamaica White Females, 1928; A:974 x 6 #9 (Box Series I-62)
    - Caucasian x Negro--Jamaica White Males, 1928; A:974 x 6 #10 (Box Series I-62)
    - Caucasian x Indian, 1920-1925; A:974 x 7 (Box Series I-62)
    - Caucasian x Hawaiian, 1942; A:974 x 96 (Box Series I-62)
    - Caucasian x Eskimo, 1927; A:974 x 98 (Box Series I-62)
    - Europe, 1915-1919; A:9740 (Box Series I-62)
    - Irish - Greek, 1923; A:97·415 x 87 (Box Series I-62)
    - English - Armenian, 1923; A:97·42 x 495 (Box Series I-62)
    - English - Japanese, 1913, 1923; A:97·42 x 52 (Box Series I-62)
    - Anglo-Indian, 1928; A:97·42 x 54 (Box Series I-62)
    - Germany, 1927; A:9743 (Box Series I-62)
    - Germany x Italy, 1923; A:97·43 x 45 (Box Series I-62)
    - Germany x Greece, 1923; A:97·43 x 87 (Box Series I-62)
    - Poland, 1923; A:97438 (Box Series I-62)
    - France, 1920; A:9744 (Box Series I-62)
    - Best Mothers in France, 1924; A:9744 x 427 (Box Series I-62)
    - Polish - Italian, 1923; A:9745 x 438 (Box Series I-62)
    - Spanish - Swiss - Irish, 1923; A:9746 x 494 x 415 (Box Series I-62)
    - 1915, A:974 x 6 x 7#1 (Box Series I-62)
    - 1915, A:974 x 6 x 7#2 (Box Series I-62)
  - A:974 x 6 x 7 - A:974744 (Box Series I-63)
    - 1915, A:974 x 6 x 7#3 (Box Series I-63)
    - 1915, A:974 x 6 x 7#4 (Box Series I-63)
    - 1915, A:974 x 6 x 7#5 (Box Series I-63)
    - 1915, A:974 x 6 x 7#6 (Box Series I-63)
    - 1915, A:974 x 6 x 7#7 (Box Series I-63)
    - 1915, A:974 x 6 x 7#8 (Box Series I-63)
    - 1915, A:974 x 6 x 7#9 (Box Series I-63)
    - 1915, A:974 x 6 x 7 #10 (Box Series I-63)
    - 1915, A:974 x 6 x 7 #11 (Box Series I-63)
    - Study of Commack, Suffolk County, NY, 1921; A:974:725 #1 (Box Series I-63)
    - Study of Commack, Suffolk County, NY, 1921; A:974:725 #2 (Box Series I-63)
    - Study of Commack, Suffolk County, NY, 1921; A:974:725 #3 (Box Series I-63)
    - English x Siamese, n.d.; A:97·42 x 542 (Box Series I-63)
    - Russia, 1924; A:9747 (Box Series I-63)
    - Finns and Finland [ contains photos], 1918; A:97471 (Box Series I-63)
    - Ukrainian x Russian, 1929; A:974737 x 9747 (Box Series I-63)
    - Baltic States, 1815-1934; A:97474 (Box Series I-63)
    - Lithuania, 1924; A:974744 (Box Series I-63)
  - A:9748 - A:9770 #3 (Box Series I-64)
    - Scandinavia [ contains photos], 1919, 1925; A:9748 (Box Series I-64)
    - Netherlands, 1922, 1930; A:97492 (Box Series I-64)
    - Belgium, 1930; A:97493 (Box Series I-64)
    - Serbia, 1918; A:97497 (Box Series I-64)
    - Asia, 1925; A:975 (Box Series I-64)
    - China [ contains photos], 1921-1934; A:9751 (Box Series I-64)
    - Chinese - Negro, 1924; A:97·51 x 6 (Box Series I-64)
    - Chinese - Hawaiian, 1926-1927; A:97·51 x 96 (Box Series I-64)
    - Japan, 1924, 1926; A:9752 (Box Series I-64)
    - Korea, 1919; A:97522 (Box Series I-64)
    - Jews, 1923; A:97535 (Box Series I-64)
    - Jews--Anthropometry, 1930; A:97535·011 (Box Series I-64)
    - Jews--Nervousness, 1919; A:97535·4612 (Box Series I-64)
    - India - Ceylon [ contains photos], 1928; A:9754 (Box Series I-64)
    - (Dutch - East Indian) "Mestizos of Kisar", 1922; A:97·54 x 492 (Box Series I-64)
    - Negro, 1911-1930; A:976 (Box Series I-64)
    - "Ishmael Pictures (As Many As Could Be Found in April, 1933)" [ contains photos], "Dr. H.H. Estabrook" (Box Series I-64)
      - The Tribe of Ishmael, n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Collection of photographs with short captions, relating the state of "feeble-mindedness." (Box Series I-64)
    - American Indian - Negro, 1919-1928; A:976 x 70 (Box Series I-64)
    - Negro - Albino, 1925; A:976·124 (Box Series I-64)
    - Negro - Red-Haired, 1926; A:976·1465 (Box Series I-64)
    - 1928, A:97·6 x 535 (Box Series I-64)
    - Negro - Chinaman, 1921; A:976 x 9 (Box Series I-64)
    - North Africa, 1861-1922; A:9761 #1 (Box Series I-64)
    - North Africa, 1868; A:9761 #2 (Box Series I-64)
    - West Central Africa - Sources of American Slaves, 1928-1929; A:9765 (Box Series I-64)
    - West Africa - Gold Coast, 1922-1928; A:9766 (Box Series I-64)
    - South Central Africa, 1853, 1906; A:9767 (Box Series I-64)
    - South Africa [ contains photos], 1892-1932; A:9768 (Box Series I-64)
    - Indian Photographs, Bureau of American Ethnography, 1870-1912; A:9770 #1 (Box Series I-64)
      - Bird Chief, 1870-1912 (Box Series I-64)
      - Kangi-sha-pa or Black Crow, 1870-1912 (Box Series I-64)
      - Honii-wotoma or Wolf Robe, 1870-1912 (Box Series I-64)
    - Shinnecock Indians, 1933; A:9770 #2 (Box Series I-64)
    - American Indians, 1920-1934; A:9770 #3 (Box Series I-64)
  - A:9770-1-118 - A:9861 (Box Series I-65)
    - Indians from Oklahoma (Work Sent in by Mr. Paul Roofe), 1926; A:9770-1-118 (Box Series I-65)
    - Pan-American Code, 1927; A:9770-97728-9780 (Box Series I-65)
    - Mexico, 1925; A:9772 (Box Series I-65)
    - Central America, 1925; A:97728 (Box Series I-65)
    - West Indies, 1928; A:97729 (Box Series I-65)
    - South America, 1922; A:9780 (Box Series I-65)
    - Greeks--Photographs, n.d.; A:9787 (Box Series I-65)
    - Caucasian - Eskimo, 1919; A:979 x 80 (Box Series I-65)
    - Australia, 1914-1915; A:9794 (Box Series I-65)
    - New Zealand, 1934; A:97941 (Box Series I-65)
    - New Guinea [ contains photos], 1918-1928; A:9795 (Box Series I-65)
      - Chief Pantagal, 1918; A:9795-1 (Box Series I-65)
    - Eskimos, 1908-1929; A:9798 (Box Series I-65)
    - Philippine Islands, 1923-1935; A:979914 (Box Series I-65)
    - Prehistoric Skulls, 1921, 1933; A:98 (Box Series I-65)
    - White Indians - San Blas Coast [ contains photos], 1924-1925; A:9861 (Box Series I-65)
      - Cuna children, 1924-1925 (Box Series I-65)
      - Cuna family, 1924-1925 (Box Series I-65)
      - Albino Indians of Panama, 1924; 1.0 Item(s); Mounted photographs of "White Indians" from the Marsh-Darien Expedition, 1924. (Box Series I-65)
    - Photographs #1, n.d.; --- (Box Series I-65)
      - Mongolian Idiocy, n.d. (Box Series I-65)
    - Photographs #2, 1918-1922; --- (Box Series I-65)
      - Alice Bounds ("Bear Lady"), and Mother, 1921 (Box Series I-65)
      - Baby Doll, n.d. (Box Series I-65)
      - Lady Little, Baron Paucci, and Wee Jeanie, 1921 (Box Series I-65)
      - Lionel, the Man-lion at age 5, n.d. (Box Series I-65)
      - Matjos and Bela lifting weights, 1918 (Box Series I-65)
      - Sabella Rogers with Matjos, Bela, and girl, 1918 (Box Series I-65)
      - Woman with facial hair, n.d. (Box Series I-65)
- Series II. Trait Card Boxes, 1904-1939 (Box Series II: 1-13)
  contains trait schedules, newspaper clippings, photographs, hair samples, postcard pictures, and some correspondence about specific traits. Like materials in Series I, items are organized according to the trait numbers listed in The Trait Book. Trait schedules within each number classification are arranged alphabetically by family name.
  This series contains 13 card file boxes. (See series description.)
- Series III. Family Traits Card Boxes, 1920s-1930s (Box Series III: 1-2)
  Indexes of Record of Family Traits (RFT) schedules and Family-Tree Folder (FTF) schedules. Cards in Box #1 cross-index the names of individuals who completed RFT schedules and whose surnames differ from the family name. Each card contains both surnames and includes an alpha-numeric code that was assigned to the family name, e.g., Hea-26 for Heard. (See description of Series IV.) Cards are arranged alphabetically by the surname located in the left-hand corner. Box #2 is an alphabetically arranged card catalog of the names and addresses of people who submitted FTF schedules. The cards include cross-references to schedules filed by specific trait ("A") numbers in Series I. Also included at the back of this box are similar indexes that are cross-referenced to the marriage ("M") file and to the family Traits ("D") file, which are on microfilm. For further information on interpreting the index cards and their letter codes, see Appendix A.
  This series contains 2 card file boxes. (See series description.)
- Series IV. RFT Submitters Card Catalog, 1910s-1930s (Box Series IV: 1-13)
  Card catalog of the names and addresses of people who submitted Record of Family Traits schedules to the Eugenics Record Office. Each family was given an alpha-numeric code (for example, Hea-26 for Heard), and the cards are filed by these codes. The catalog covers the alphabet from A to S; the alphabet from T to Z is missing. Some cards contain cross-references (using codes) to other families.
  - A - Be (Box Series IV-1)
  - Bi - Br (Box Series IV-2)
  - Bu - Cz (Box Series IV-3)
  - D - E (Box Series IV-4)
  - F - Go (Box Series IV-5)
  - Gr - He (Box Series IV-6)
  - Hi - J (Box Series IV-7)
  - K - L1 (Box Series IV-8)
  - Lo - Mh (Box Series IV-9)
  - Mi - O (Box Series IV-10)
  - P - Richards (Box Series IV-11)
  - Richardson - Sh (Box Series IV-12)
  - Si - Sz (Box Series IV-13)
- Series V. Record of Family Traits, 1911-1940 (Box Series V-1)
  A sample of the material that is now at the Center for Human Genetics in Bar Harbor, Maine. The sample includes one folder of originals and three folders of photocopies of completed Record of Family Traits schedules. These schedules record information about several generations of families, including names, birthplaces, birthdates, illnesses, and special abilities.
  - Original Files, B-V, 1939-1940 (Box Series V-1)
  - Photocopies of Files (Box Series V-1)
    - Folder #1, Lab-Lad, 1911-1932 (Box Series V-1)
    - Folder #2, Lad-Lai, 1919-1935 (Box Series V-1)
    - Folder #3, Lai-Lak, 1918-1934 (Box Series V-1)
- Series VI. Fitter Family Studies, 1913-1936 (Box Series VI: 1-5)
  Fitter Families Examinations given in the states of Arkansas, Kansas, Massachusetts, Michigan, Oklahoma, and Texas from 1925 to 1927. These folders are filed by state. This series also includes some clippings about eugenics in law; two folders of Individual Analysis Cards for the years 1917-1936 (filed alphabetically by last name); some correspondence with the Eugenics Registry at the Race Betterment Foundation; and biographical reports and eugenics information for many individuals, some of them potential field workers for the Eugenics Record Office (filed alphabetically by last name at the end of this series). For some further information about Fitter Family Studies, see the card file located in Series VII.
  - [Case Studies by S.C. Devitt], 1919 (Box Series VI-1)
  - Eugenics in Law, 1913-1934 (Box Series VI-1)
  - "Eugenics Register", 16 May 1918 (Box Series VI-1)
  - Fitter Families Examinations--Arkansas (Box Series VI-1)
    - Folder #1, 1925 (Box Series VI-1)
    - Folder #2, 1927 (Box Series VI-1)
    - Folder #3, 1927 (Box Series VI-1)
  - Fitter Families Examinations--Kansas (Box Series VI-1)
    - Folder #1, 1925 (Box Series VI-1)
    - Folder #2, 1925 (Box Series VI-1)
    - Folder #3, 1925 (Box Series VI-1)
    - Folder #4, 1925 (Box Series VI-1)
    - Folder #5, 1927 (Box Series VI-1)
    - Folder #6, 1927 (Box Series VI-1)
  - Fitter Families Examinations--Massachusetts (Box Series VI-2)
    - Folder #1, 1925 (Box Series VI-2)
    - Folder #2, 1925 (Box Series VI-2)
    - Folder #3, 1925 (Box Series VI-2)
    - Folder #4, 1925 (Box Series VI-2)
    - Folder #5, 1926 (Box Series VI-2)
  - Fitter Families Examinations--Michigan (Box Series VI-2)
    - Folder #1, 1925 (Box Series VI-2)
    - Folder #2, 1925 (Box Series VI-2)
    - Folder #3, 1925 (Box Series VI-2)
    - Folder #4, 1928 (Box Series VI-2)
    - Folder #5, 1928 (Box Series VI-2)
    - Folder #6, 1928 (Box Series VI-2)
  - Fitter Families Examinations--Oklahoma, 1925 (Box Series VI-3)
  - Fitter Families Examinations--Texas (Box Series VI-3)
    - Folder #1, 1925 (Box Series VI-3)
    - Folder #2, 1925 (Box Series VI-3)
    - Folder #3, 1925 (Box Series VI-3)
    - Folder #4, 1925 (Box Series VI-3)
    - Folder #5, 1925 (Box Series VI-3)
    - Folder #6, 1926 (Box Series VI-3)
    - Folder #7, 1926 (Box Series VI-3)
    - Folder #8, 1927 (Box Series VI-3)
    - Folder #9, 1927 (Box Series VI-3)
  - Individual Analysis Cards (Box Series VI-4)
    - Folder #1, A-Ma, 1920-1936 (Box Series VI-4)
      - Individual Analysis Card from Fitter Family Study, Example (redacted), 1922 (Box Series VI-4)
    - Folder #2, Me-W, 1917-1931 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Kansas Free Fair, 1924-1928 (Box Series VI-4)
    - Fitter Families' Examination. Kansas Free Fair. Topeka, 1924 (Box Series VI-4)
      Nineteen page, blank examination form with some annotation.
    - Fitter Families for Georgia, 1924 (Box Series VI-4)
    - Floor Plan of Eugenics Building, Kansas Free Fair, Topeka, 1928 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Race Betterment Foundation. Eugenics Registry, 1917-1918 (Box Series VI-4)
  - "Selected List of 500 Best Family Records", 1917 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Agen, Meyer, 1915 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Archer, Constance, 1924 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Armstrong, Florence Azella, 1915 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Babcock, Margaret Rosetta, 1921 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Banta, James; Leah Margaret; Ruth, 1924 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Barrett, Louise Morris, 1926 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Blauvelt, Jessie A., 1921 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Bleeker, Mrs., 1923 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Burt, Luella, 1931 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Caum, Edward Leonard, 1915 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Cochran, John, 1928 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Cowdery, Karl Montague, 1915 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Crane, Harry Wolven, 1915 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Danko, Walter, 1924 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Disbrow, Thelma, 1920 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Douglass, Edith Manson, 1915 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Dunbar, Alice Miriam, 1919 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Eddy, Corinne Schenck, 1921 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Frost, Lillian Adele, 1917 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Funnell, Sarah Louise, 1915 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Gould, Joseph Ferdinand, 1915 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Gower, Charlotte Gray, 1920 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Hart, Adelaide M., 1915 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Holmes, Olive T., 1920 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Holowata, Mary, 1926 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Jenkins, Mary Elizabeth, 1923 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Joy, Grace Mae, 1921 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Keeler, Clyde, 1929 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Kesler, Margaret, 1920 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Kirkman, John, 1916 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Liddle, Ruth Howe, 1920 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Lloyd, Bess Lucile, 1921 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Lockwood, Mildred Harriett, 1921 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Loomis, Agnes Brooke; Emily Fidelia; Hiram Benjamin, 1918 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Martin, Margaret, 1927, 1931 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Matthews, Mabel Ann, 1915 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Mead, Pauline Anderson, 1921 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Milliard, Mrs., 1923 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Myers, Sadie Rae, 1915 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Nascher, Ignatz Leo, 1917 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Osborn, Margaret Stanton, 1920 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Parshley, Elsa M.; Thomas Frederickson, 1923 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Perry, Allie Plesant Bear, 1918 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Pickett, Alice N., 1925-1926 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Pierce, Julia G., 1915 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Pointon, Phyllis, 1921 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Rogers, Evelyn, 1924 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Russell, Laura Catherine, 1921 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Sherman, Blanche, 1920 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Taylor, Olivia, 1926 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Thurber, Carmine; Frank, Jr., n.d. (Box Series VI-5)
  - Walmsley, MacGregor, 1920 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Welch, William, 1917 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Wellington, Gladys Broeffle, 1920 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Whitefield, Isabelle Mary, 1921 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Whitney, L. Jean, 1915 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Woods, Emily Wingate, 1915 (Box Series VI-5)
- Series VII. Field Worker Files, 1911-1926 (Box Series VII: 1-2)
  A sample of the material that is now at the Center for Human Genetics in Bar Harbor, Maine. The sample includes photocopies of biographical sketches and pedigrees that were taken by field workers of the Eugenics Record Office. There are some original documents. Seventeen field workers are represented in the sample, filed by field worker number. These numbers are given in a list filed under "Numbers of Eugenics Record Office Field Workers." Also in this series are notes from a field workers meeting in 1915 and a notebook that contains suggestions for the field workers about methods of keeping notes. The card file (1911-1926) in this series gives a record of each field worker by number and by name, as well as by subject and geographical location covered. The card file also includes some entries containing information on Fitter Family Studies.
  - Devitt, S.C., #2 (Box Series VII-1)
    - Folder #1, 1914-1917 (Box Series VII-1)
    - Folder #2, 1917, n.d. (Box Series VII-1)